《行尸走肉》
我要去找他们
I'm going after them.
别 我们不知道他们在哪儿
Don't, they could be anywhere.
而且兰德尔若是跑回来 这里需要你
And if Randall come back, we're gonna need you here.
- 瑞克和肖恩还没回来 - 没
- Rick and Shane ain't back? - No.
- 我们听见了枪声 - 也许他们找到了兰德尔
- We heard a shot. - Maybe they found Randall.
- 我们找到他了 - 把他押回棚屋了吗
- We found him. - Is he back in the shed?
他变成了行尸
He's a walker.
找到咬他的行尸了吗
Did you find the walker that bit him?
奇怪的是他没有被咬
No, the weird thing is he wasn't bit.
- 他脖子断了 - 所以他死前挣扎过
- His neck was broke. - So he fought back.
问题是肖恩和兰德尔的
The thing is, Shane and Randall's tracks.
足迹重合
were right on top of each other.
肖恩不会追踪 所以他不可能跟在后面
And Shane ain't no tracker, so he didn't come up behind him.
他们走在一起
They were together.
拜托你去外面把瑞克和肖恩找回来
Would you please get back out there, find Rick and Shane.
搞清楚到底发生了什么好吗
and find out what on earth is going on?
- 好吧 - 谢谢
- You got it. - Thank you.
你被咬了吗
You bit too?
没
No.
肖恩被咬了
Shane was.
那不是肖恩了 你知道的
That wasn't Shane. You know that.
以前是
Used to be.
发生了什么
What happened?
你们被袭击了
You guys attacked?
我有听到枪声
I mean, I… I heard a gunshot,
但我没在周围看见行尸
but I didn't see any walkers nearby.
肖恩到底是怎么死的
How did Shane die?
我的天 走 快走
Oh my God! Go-go-go-go…
我们得回去房子里
We… we gotta get to the house,
- 告诉其他人 - 我们没法回去
- tell the others. - We'll never get through that.
绕不过去
Can't go around.
卡尔 跟紧点 快走
Carl, stay close. Go!
- 帕特里夏 关灯 - 我去拿枪
- Patricia, kill the lights. - I'll get the guns.
也许它们和公路那尸群一样只是路过
Maybe they're just passing, like the herd on the highway.
我们是不是该进屋
Should we just go inside?
屋子里又没有秘密地下通道
Not unless there's a tunnel downstairs I don't know about.
这种规模的尸群足以把房子碾平
A herd that size would rip the house down.
- 卡尔不在 - 什么
- Carl's gone. - What?
他在楼上 但我找不到他
He… he was upstairs. I can't find him anymore.
- 也许是躲起来了 - 他应该就在楼上
- Maybe he's hiding. - He's supposed to be upstairs.
- 我不会抛下我儿子逃走的 - 不会
- I'm not leaving without my boy. - We're not.
我们再找找 一定会找到他的
We're gonna look again. We're gonna find him.
玛姬
Maggie.
俺们村里长大的都会用枪
You grow up country, you pick up a thing or two.
看这数量 有枪也没用
I got the number… It's no use.
你想走可以走
You can go if you want.
你要把它们全灭了吗
You gonna take 'em all on?
我们有枪 有车
We have guns. We have cars.
能杀多少杀多少
Kill as many as we can,
然后用汽车把剩下的引走
and we'll use the cars to lead the rest of them off the farm.
- 你说真的吗 - 这是我的农场
- Are you serious? - This is my farm.
我誓死不弃
I'll die here.
好吧 我反正无所谓
All right. It's as good a night as any.
好了 来吧
All right, here we go.
好了 快点
Come on. Hurry.
妈的 好 好了
Oh shit. All right. Okay.
到上面去 快
Up there. Hurry.
- 那你呢 - 我一会就上去
- Well, what about you? - I'll be right there.
我一下令你就放火
Drop the lighter when I say.
至少阻止一部分行尸接近房子
We'll stop some of them from reaching the house.
引开剩下的 这样我们还有一线生机
and distract the others, so at least we'll have a chance.
看着我 你能做到的
Hey-hey-hey, look at me. You can do this.
卡尔
Carl…
我爱你
I love you.
好了 快走
All right, go-go-go.
想大开荤戒吗
You want some?!
过来吃啊
Come and get it!
来啊 来啊
Come on! Come on!
来啊
Come on!
来这儿
Over here!
过来这儿 过来这儿
Come on, over here. Come on, over here!
卡尔 就是现在
Carl, now!
- 开稳点 - 我尽力
- Keep it steady! - I'm trying!
见鬼
Damn it.
谷仓着火了
The barn's on fire.
行尸们被引过去了
They're headed for it.
也许是瑞克放的火
Maybe Rick set it to draw 'em in.
我找不到他
I can't find him anywhere.
- 也许他偷偷溜出去了 - 我该怎么办
- So maybe he snuck outside. - What do I do?
他刚才还在这
He was here.
他一定是去找瑞克了
He must've run off, maybe looking for Rick.
- 或者他去追兰德尔了 - 可能是他放的火
- or went after Randall himself. - Maybe he set the fire.
一定是瑞克或者肖恩放的火
Must've been Rick or Shane who started that fire.
可能他们正在往外逃呢
Maybe they're trying to get out back!
- 你到周围看看 快去 - 收到
- Why don't you circle around? Go! - Got it!
嘿 我们在这
Hey! Here!
把车开到这来
Get in here!
停在这 快点
Put it right there! Come on!
哦 不
Oh no!
卡尔 快
Carl, now!
走这边
This way!
它们到处都是 没法围住它们
They're all over the place. There's no corralling them.
就算子弹用完也没什么用
We're gonna run out of ammo before we even make a dent.
我们需要新的计划
We need a new game plan.
那里 往树林里跑
There. Head for the woods now,
越快越好 快跑
as fast as you can. Come on.
快点
Come on!
我检查了小屋 哪儿都找不到他
I checked the shed. I can't find him anywhere.
地下室和阁楼都没有
Not in the cellar or the attic.
他怎么就不能听一回话呢
Why can't he listen for once?
如果他跟着他爸走 走得就是那条路
Ok okay, if he followed his daddy, he went that way.
不 你会把行尸引到他那边去的
No, you'll lead 'em right to him.
我们不能久留
We can't stay here!
- 那是我儿子 - 你要相信我
- That's my boy! - You're gonna have to trust.
如果我们找到他 他需要见到他妈妈
If we find him, he's gonna need his mother.
我们必须走了
We've gotta go.
叫上其他人
Get the others.
卡尔
Carl!
贝丝 帕特里夏 快点 我们得走了
Beth, Patricia, come on. We've gotta go now.
洛莉
Lori.
赫谢尔
Hershel.
Hershel. Hershel!
- 赫谢尔 该走了 - 快点
- Hershel, it's time to go! - Come on! Now!
赫谢尔
Hershel! Hershel!
我们得走了 我们得离开这里
We gotta go. We gotta get out of here.
- 我们走吧 - 躲在我后边
- We gotta go. - Stay behind me. Stay behind me.
大家快点
Come on, girls. Come on.
不
No! No!
- 上车 - 爸爸
- Get in! - Dad!
去找卡萝尔 她往那个方向跑了
Get Carol… She ran that way.
小心点
Look out!
它们抓住她了 我们得走了
They got her! We gotta go!
T仔 快
Dog, come on!
他们要去哪儿
Where the hell are they going?
我跟着他们吗
Should I follow them?
跟着
I'd say yes.
快转弯 在这快转弯
Swing it around. Swing it around here.
天呐
Oh my God.
我开不进去
I can't get through.
- 往外开 - 什么
- Head out. - What?
- 立刻离开农场 - 别那么说
- Get off the farm now. - Don't say that.
- 玛姬 农场完了 - 我们不能丢下其他人
- Maggie, it's lost! - The others… we can't leave them.
快离开农场
Get off the farm now!
快点
Come on!
洛莉呢 你看见洛莉了吗
Where's Lori? Did you see Lori?
我不知道发生了什么 瑞克
I don't know what happened, Rick.
它们没完没了
They just keep coming.
像瘟疫一样 它们到处都是
It's like a plague. They're everywhere.
洛莉 你看到她了吗
Lori! Did you see her?
- 没有 - 我们得走了
- No! - We have to go.
去找妈妈和其他人
Find mom and the others.
- 这是我的农场 - 现在不是了
- It's my farm! - Not anymore!
- 快点 - 来呀 你们来呀
- Come on! - Come on! Come on!
- 快点 - 赫谢尔
- Come on! - Hershel!
快点
Come on!
走
Go.
瑞克 等等
Rick! Rick! Wait!
快点 我时间有限
Come on, I ain't got all day!
我们走
Let's go!
天呐
Oh my God. Oh my God.
好吧 我们绕回公路
All right, let's just… Let's just circle back to the highway.
你看见我爸爸了吗 他逃出来了吗
Did you see my dad? Did… did he make it?
- 你看见了吗 - 我什么都没看见
- Did you see? - I couldn't see anything.
我把贝丝弄丢了 我们回去吧
And Beth… I lost Beth. We've gotta go back there.
我们不能回去
We can't go back, okay?
那里什么也没有了
There's nothing to go back to.
但是贝丝
But Beth…
她应该和洛莉在一起呢
I-I… I think she was with Lori.
- 他们逃出来了吗 - 我不知道
- Did they make it? - I don't know.
帕特里夏呢 吉米呢
Patricia? Jimmy?
如果他们没逃出来怎么办
What if they didn't make it?
如果没人逃出来怎么办
What if nobody made it?
他们逃出来了
They made it, okay?
他们一定逃出来了
They had to.
好吧 我们把车开回
All right, let's just circle around.
给索菲亚留食物的地方
to the highway where we left supplies for Sophia.
不 尸群是从那个方向来的
No, the herd came from that direction.
停车 把车停下
Just stop. Stop the car.
停车
Stop the car.
我来开
Let me drive.
玛姬 看着我
Hey, Maggie, look at me. Look at me.
我们还活着 我们逃出来了
Hey, we're alive. We made it.
好吗 我相信他们也一样
Okay? I'm sure they are, too.
好吗
Right?
我爱你
I love you.
玛姬 我爱你
Maggie, I love you.
我很早之前就应该告诉你
I should've said it a long time ago.
我爱你很久了
and it's been true for a long time.
我们会没事的 好吗
We're gonna be all right, okay?
我们会没事的
We'll be all right.
好的 好
Okay. Yeah.
等等 妈妈在哪儿
Wait, where's mom?
你说过她会在这里的
You said she'd be here.
我们得回去找她
We… we gotta go back for her.
- 卡尔 - 不 我们为什么要逃走
- Carl… - No. Why are we running?
你在做什么
What are you doing?
她可是我妈妈
It's… it is mom.
我们应该找到她
We need to get her.
而不是在一英里外的地方等她来
and not be safe a mile away.
嘘 安静一点好吗 拜托了
Shh. You need to be quiet, all right? Please.
拜托
Please…
是妈妈呀
It's mom.
- 听着 卡尔 - 不要
- Look, Carl, listen… - No.
瑞克
Rick.
你应该把你儿子送到安全的地方
You've got to get your boy to safety.
我留下来等我女儿和其他人
I'll wait here for my girls and the others.
我知道一些地方
I know a few places.
我们挑一个 之后在那碰头
We'll meet up at one of them later.
哪儿 哪里是安全的
Where? Where is safe?
我们不能分开
We're not splitting up.
求你了
Please,
一定要确保你儿子的安全
keep your boy safe.
我会躲在一辆车里
I'll hide in one of the cars.
如果行尸抓到我 那就是命
If a walker gets me, so be it.
我已经失去了我的农场
I've lost my farm.
我的妻子 还可能失去了我的女儿们
I've lost my wife and maybe my daughters.
你并不确定
You don't know that.
他们会过来的
They'll be here.
你也不确定这一点
And you don't know that.
你是信奉上帝的人
You're a man of God.
有点信念吧
Have some faith.
我不能说
I can't profess.
自己明白上帝的安排
to understand God's plan,
但是耶稣曾预言让死者复生
but Christ promised the resurrection of the dead.
可是现在的情景
I just thought he had something.
跟我预想的完全不同
a little different in mind.
我们待在一起
We stick together.
我们得回去
Hey, we gotta turn around.
再去面对那些尸群吗
Straight back to that herd?
不行
Um, no.
高速公路那里 他们都会去那的
The highway's back there. That's where they'll be.
瑞克会回到我们最开始停下的地方
Rick will go back to where we first broke down.
- 格伦也一样 - 我们正向东开
- and Glenn too. - We're headed east,
去海岸 我们一开始就应该直接去那
get to the coast. We should've done that from the jump.
我们好不容易才逃出来
Look, we've got a shot to get out of here in one piece.
我得找到卡尔
I gotta find Carl.
他也许和别人一块逃出来了
He may have escaped with somebody.
不好意思 但他们只能靠自己了
I hate to say it, but they're on their own.
我们都不知道去哪找他们
There's no way to even begin to start looking.
你错了
You're wrong.
听着 我们不能回去
Look, we can't go back.
很抱歉 这是找死
I'm sorry. It's suicide.
好吧 那让我下车
All right, then let me out.
往回开 要不然我们就下车
Then turn around, or you let us out right now.
我应该就让你们走 好吧
I should do it, you know. Okay?
T仔
T-Dog.
你简直疯了
You're out of your damn minds.
好了 过来 快过来
Okay. Come come come come.
我不知道咱们还能在这待多久
I don't know how much longer we can stay here.
没有等到妈妈我是不会离开的
I… I'm not leaving without mom.
我们就这么离开吗
So we're just gonna walk away?
我妻子和你女儿们也许还活着
Not knowing if my wife, your girls are still out there?
我们怎么能这么做
How do we live with that?
你现在最需要关心的
You've only got one concern now…
只有一件事
just one…
确保他活下来
keeping him alive.
老天爷也许不按规矩出牌
Nature may be throwing us a curveball,
但保护孩子依然是最重要的
but that law is still true.
卡尔
Carl.
这里不安全
It's not safe here.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们…
We'll…
谢天谢地
Oh thank God!
你是在哪找到大家的
Where'd you find everyone?
有人的车在路上胡乱变道
Well, those guys' tail lights zigzagging all over the road…
只有亚洲人才会开得这么臭
figured he had to be Asian, driving like that.
真好笑
Good one.
其他人呢
Where's the rest of us?
逃到这里的只有我们这些人
We're the only ones who made it so far.
肖恩呢
Shane?
安德莉亚呢
Andrea?
她救了我 然后我就没见到她了
She saved me, then I lost her.
我们看见她被扑倒了
We saw her go down.
帕德里夏呢
Patricia?
它们也把她夺走了
They got her, too.
就在我面前 我当时
Took her right in front of me. I was…
我拉着她不放 爸爸 可她
I was holdin' onto her, daddy. She just…
那吉米呢 你们看见吉米了吗
What about Jimmy? Did you see Jimmy?
他在房车里 行尸攻了进去
He was in the RV. It got overrun.
你确定看见安德莉亚了
You definitely saw Andrea?
到处都是行尸
There were walkers everywhere.
你看见她了没
Did you see her?
- 我要回去 - 不行
- I'm gonna go back. - No.
我们不能扔下她
We can't just leave her.
我们根本不知道她在不在那儿
We don't even know if she's there.
她不在那儿 不在那儿
She isn't there. She isn't.
她肯定跑了 或者死了
She's somewhere else or she's dead.
肯定找不到的
There's no way to find her.
那我们连找都不找吗
So we're not even gonna look for her?
我们得继续逃命
We gotta keep moving.
这里到处都是行尸
There have been walkers crawling all over here.
我觉得应该往东走
I say head east.
远离大路
Stay off the main roads.
越是大路 越多行尸
The bigger the road, the more walkers,
越多这种畜生 看我宰了他
more assholes like this one. I got him.
见鬼
Damn it.
糟了
Oh shit!
该死
Damn.
怎么了
What's wrong?
油表警示灯已经亮了一小时了
We've been riding red for the past hour.
最好告诉他们一声
Better make sure we don't get forgot.
你没油了吗
You out?
油箱早见底了
Running on fumes.
我们不能待在这儿
We can't stay here.
一台车挤不下这么多人
We can't all fit in one car.
那明早去弄点油回来
Well, then make a run for some gas in the morning.
- 要在这儿过夜吗 - 我好冷
- Spend the night here? - I'm freezing.
我们会生篝火 好吗
We'll build a fire, yeah?
你们去找点柴火 别走散了
You go out looking for firewood, stay close.
只有这么多箭了 你还有子弹吗
Only got so many arrows. How you doing on ammo?
不多了
Not enough.
我们不能傻鸡巴坐着 暴露自己
We can't just sit here with our asses hanging out.
说话文明点
Watch your mouth.
大家别慌 听瑞克的
Everyone stop panicking and listen to Rick.
好吧 我们设好防线岗哨
All right, we'll set up a perimeter.
明天一早去找点汽油和补给
In the morning, we'll find gas and some supplies.
然后继续前进
We'll keep pushing on.
我和格伦现在就可以跑一趟
Glenn and I can go make a run now,
- 去找点汽油 - 不行 我们要待在一起
- try and scrounge up some gas. - No, we stay together.
万一发生什么
God forbid something happens.
没车我们会寸步难行
and people get stranded without a car.
瑞克 我们现在就寸步难行
Rick, we're stranded now.
我知道现在情况很糟
I know it looks bad,
我们经历了风风雨雨
we've all been through hell and worse,
但至少大家没走散
but at least we found each other.
我本来不确定能重聚…
I wasn't sure… I really wasn't…
但我们做到了 我们还在一起
but we did. We're together.
我们要保持这样
We keep it that way.
我们会找到庇护所的 肯定能找到
We'll find shelter somewhere. There's gotta be a place.
瑞克 你看看周围
Rick, look around. Okay?
到处都是行尸 他们好像在迁徙
There's walkers everywhere. They're migrating or something.
肯定有个地方 不仅能让我们躲藏
There's gotta be a place not just where we hole up,
而且能防御
but that we fortify,
能坚守 能把大家重整旗鼓
hunker down, pull ourselves together,
重建我们的生活
build a life for each other.
我知道一定有这么个地方 我们要找到它
I know it's out there. We just have to find it.
就算我们找到了个地方
Even if we do find a place.
就算我们觉得它是安全的
and we think it's safe,
但能撑多久却永远说不准
we can never be sure. For how long?
想想农场发生的事
Look what happened with the farm.
我们很傻很天真地以为那里很安全
We fooled ourselves into thinking that that was safe.
我们不会再犯那个错误
We won't make that mistake again.
我们今晚露营
We'll make camp tonight.
就在那边 休整一天后继续前进
over there, get on the road at the break of day.
你觉得这可行吗
Does this feel right to you?
万一行尸来了怎么办
What if walkers come through,
又来一伙像兰德尔的人怎么办
or another group like Randall's?
你知道我找到了兰德尔吧
You know I found Randall, right?
他变异了 但他没被咬过
He had turned, but he wasn't bit.
- 怎么会这样 - 瑞克 到底怎么回事
- How's that possible? - Rick, what the hell happened?
肖恩杀了兰德尔
Shane killed Randall.
他一直就想这么干
Just like he always wanted to.
然后尸群抓住了他吗
And then the herd got him?
我们都被感染了
We're all infected.
- 什么 - 在疾控中心时
- What? - At the CDC,
詹纳告诉我的
Jenner told me.
不管它是什么
Whatever it is,
我们都是携带者
we all carry it.
你却一句都没告诉我们
And you never said anything?
说了又能怎样
Would it have made a difference?
你一直都知道吗
You knew this whole time?
我又不知道是真的
How could I have known for sure?
你知道那个家伙有多疯…
You saw how crazy that mo…
你凭什么不说啊
That is not your call.
当我发现谷仓里的行尸时
Okay, when I found out about the walkers in the barn,
我为了大家好 告诉了大家
I told, for the good of everyone.
我觉得大家最好别知道这事
Well, I thought it best that people didn't know.
我知道你有自己的苦衷
I'm sure you had your reasons.
- 有什么我能… - 我杀了他
- Is there anything that… - I killed him.
我杀了肖恩
I killed Shane.
他想杀我
He came at me.
他杀了兰德尔 把我引进树林
He killed Randall to get me into the woods.
他计划好的
He planned it.
我…别无选择
I had… I had no choice.
我给了他回头的机会
I gave him every chance…
他却把我越领越远
and he kept leading me further out.
我任由他带着我走
He pushed me, and I let him.
走了一会儿
And after awhile, I knew…
我发觉了他的企图和目的
I knew what he was doing, what he was up to.
但我却还是跟着
And I kept going.
没有停步
I didn't stop.
我可以停下 但…
I could have, but…
我只想一切快点结束
I just wanted it over.
他总是不停地找茬
Dogging me every step of the way.
表现得好像是我偷了你和卡尔
Acting like I stole you and Carl, like…
好像我是他的绊脚石
like I was in the way.
我只是想快点结束
I just wanted it over.
我希望他死
I wanted him dead.
我杀了他
I killed him.
他变成了僵尸
He turned.
我才知道詹纳…
That's how I knew Jenner…
詹纳的话是真的
Jenner was right.
卡尔干掉了它
Carl put him down.
我们跟他一起不安全
We're not safe with him.
那种事竟然瞒着我们
Keeping something like that from us.
你为什么跟着他 他只会拖你后腿
Why do you need him? He's just gonna pull you down.
不 我对瑞克没意见
No. Rick's done all right by me.
你只是他的马仔
You're his henchman.
而我则是负担
and I'm a burden.
你不该屈居此位
You deserve better.
你到底想要什么
What do you want?
一个高尚的领导者
A man of honor.
瑞克很高尚
Rick has honor.
我觉得我们应该出去搏一搏
I think we should take our chances.
别傻了
Don't be foolish.
没有食物 没有燃料
There's no food, no fuel,
没有弹药
no ammo.
- 什么声音 - 什么都有可能
- What was that? - Could be anything.
可能是浣熊或者负鼠
Could be a raccoon, could be a possum.
或者行尸
Walker.
我们必须上路 还等什么
We need to leave. I mean what are we waiting for?
- 去哪里 - 声音来自那边
- Which way? - It came from over there.
- 我们来的方向 - 没错
- Back from where we came. - Yeah.
现在最忌讳
The last thing we need is.
大半夜乱跑
for everyone to be running off in the dark.
我们没车
We don't have the vehicles.
任何人都不该徒步出去
No one's traveling on foot.
不要惊慌
Don't panic.
我不想…
I'm not…
我不想待在这里等着尸群袭击
I'm not sitting here, waiting for another herd to blow through.
- 我们必须现在就离开 - 任何人都不准走
- We need to move, now. - No one is going anywhere.
- 做点什么 - 我正在做
- Do something. - I am doing something!
我在凝聚这个团队
I'm keeping this group together,
让我们活下去
alive.
我一直都在这么做
I've been doing that all along, no matter what.
你们以为我愿意吗
I didn't ask for this.
我为你们杀了我最好的朋友
I killed my best friend for you people, for Christ's sake!
你们知道他什么德性
You saw what he was like,
他总是逼我
how he pushed me,
他危及我们的安全
how he compromised us,
他是个威胁
how he threatened us.
他导演了整个兰德尔事件
He staged the whole Randall thing,
他想诱杀我
led me out to put a bullet in my back.
他让我别无选择
He gave me no choice.
他是我朋友 但是他想杀我
He was my friend, but he came after me.
我双手是干净的
My hands are clean.
也许你们离了我更好
Maybe you people are better off without me.
去吧
Go ahead.
我认为能找到容身之所
I say there's a place for us,
但也许这只是白日梦
but maybe… maybe it's just another pipe dream.
也许…我是个蠢货
Maybe… maybe I'm fooling myself again.
你们怎么不去自己找找
Why don't you… Why don't you go and find out yourself?
记得寄明信片给我
Send me a postcard.
走啊 门大敞着
Go on, there's the door.
幸福就在门外 看你们能走多远
You can do better? Let's see how far you get.
没人走 好的 但丑话说在前面…
No takers? Fine. But get one thing straight…
如果留下
you're staying.
就别再想要什么民主
This isn't a democracy anymore.